Mertz mss., 1902-2019 LMC 2914
Lilly Library
Mertz mss.
1948-2013
Lilly Library
Mertz, Barbara
Peters, Elizabeth, 1927-2013
Michaels, Barbara, 1927-2013
LMC 2914
199 Boxes 143 standard, 56 custom
1 folio oversize
The Mertz mss., 1902-2019, consist of the correspondence, writings, financial documents, clippings, personal ephemera, photographs, and research files of author Barbara Mertz, who wrote under the pen-names Elizabeth Peters and Barbara Michaels.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase: 2016
Biographical Note
Born Barbara Louise Gross in Canton, Illinois, Barbara Mertz (1927-2013) was an American author and Egyptologist. While her two non-fiction works on ancient Egypt are highly regarded in the field, Mertz is also known for the gothic and supernatural thrillers she published under the pen-name Barbara Michaels. As Elizabeth Peters, a pen-name created from the names of her two children, she wrote the extremely popular Amelia Peabody mystery series, which follows a Victorian Egyptologist, along with two other mystery series following memorable heroines: professor of art history Vicky Bliss and librarian Jacqueline Kirby. An avid gardener, cat enthusiast, lover of gin, and collector of vintage jewelry, furniture, and clothing, Mertz was also highly active in the professional development of writing and Egyptology throughout her career. In 1989, Mertz helped found Malice Domestic, a professional organization dedicated to traditional and cozy mysteries. Mertz also served as president of the American Crime Writer's League (ACWL) for a time and served on the Long Range Planning Committee of the American Research Center in Egypt (ARCE) from 1997-1999. In 1991, Mertz established the Elizabeth Peters-Barbara Michaels Scholarship at Hood College for students of color interested in pursuing a mystery writing career.
Scope and Contents
The first three series – Barbara Mertz, Elizabeth Peters, and Barbara Michaels – consist of typescripts, publicity, reviews, artwork, and correspondence relating to Mertz's publications under each corresponding pen-name, arranged chronologically by publication date and/or series. Correspondence consists of four subseries – Literary, Personal, Fanmail and Fandom, and Business – including faxes, letters, and postcards. The Literary subseries mainly consists of correspondence with agents and publishers regarding the publication of Mertz's works. The Personal subseries includes correspondence two and from Mertz's friends and family. The Fanmail and Fandom series includes fanmail (and Mertz's responses), as well as correspondence related to and used in her newsletter, MPM, and copies of the newsletter itself; also included are various fan-related items sent to or collected by Mertz. The Business subseries has some overlap with the Literary subseries, but the correspondence deals more broadly with Mertz's daily expenses, travel, and other non-publishing matters. The Other Writings series collects all of Mertz's published and unpublished works, such as speeches, short stories, and essays, that did not fall within the monograph-length bibliography of the first three series. Publicity and Appearances includes correspondence and travel ephemera related to invitations and requests for Mertz to speak at events or sign books. Also included in this series are typescripts and clippings of interviews and publicity, as well as ephemera from Mertz's appearances and talks. The Financial and Legal series includes royalty statements and publishing contracts as well as Mertz's personal and business finances, such as receipts, travel expense records, and vet bills. Subject Files include clippings, periodicals, travel guides, and notes related to various subjects, some of which Mertz researched as part of her writing process. The Egyptology subseries also includes Mertz's doctorate coursework and notes. Professional Files include correspondence, publications, drafts, handouts, and notes related to Mertz's work in professional organizations. The Writings by Others series consists of typescripts, monographs, and drafts sent to Mertz by friends and fans – including fanfiction of Mertz's own works. The Personal series includes memorabilia and correspondence relating to Mertz's personal life, as well as the lives of her parents; also included are Mertz's many awards. Photographs consist of several photo albums and loose printed photographs, as well as a collection of slides and negatives, some of which still reside in slide carousels. Finally, the Audio-Visual and Born-Digital series includes television shows about Egypt as well as travel footage filmed by Mertz herself; also included are audiobook roughs for Mertz's writings and a handful of publishing-related zip disks and CDs.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following series: Barbara Mertz, Elizabeth Peters, Barbara Michaels, Correspondence, Other Writings, Publicity and Appearances, Financial and Legal, Subject Files, Professional Files, Writings by Others, Personal, Photographs, and Audio-Visual & Born-Digital. Mertz's writings are arranged into the first three series according to the name under which they were published and arranged chronologically by publication date. Correspondence is separated according to the four original subcategorical labels – Literary, Personal, Fanmail, and Business – presumably done by either Mertz herself or Kristen Whitbread, her assistant. Within those subseries, correspondence is mostly arranged chronologically, with any subject-based folders (such as the "HarperCollins" folder in Literary Correspondence) that were originally separated out kept separate and alphabetized. The Invitations and Requests subseries within Publicity and Appearances is also arranged based on the original folders in which the materials arrived and divided into Accepted, Ignored, and Declined accordingly.
Separated Materials
Barbara Mertz's book collection, including copies of her own works as well as reference sources, was physically separated from the collection and may be found by searching IUCAT.
Egyptology; Gothic literature; Detective and mystery stories; Malice Domestic, Ltd; Peabody, Amelia, (Fictitious character)
- Barbara Mertz
  - Temples, Tombs and Hieroglyphs
    - "Dennis's comments", undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Photos and illustrations, undated; 2 Folders (Box 1, Folder 2, Box 191, Folder 14)
    - Rough draft - typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - Annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - Revised typescript, 2007; 3 Folders (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
    - Foul matter, 2007-2008; 7 Folders (Box 1, Folder 10-16)
    - Foul matter, 1960-2011; 3 Folders (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
    - Photographs, undated; 2 Folders (Box 2, Folder 4, Box 191, Folder 13)
    - Notes and lists of illustrations, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Reviews and publicity, 1964-1978; 2 Folders (Box 2, Folder 6, Box 191, Folder 11)
    - Cover proofs, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Second edition revisions, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Publishing correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 191, Folder 12)
    - Oversize cover proof, undated (Box 197)
  - Red Land, Black Land
    - Rough draft, 1965-1966; 7 Folders (Box 2, Folder 9-15)
    - Revised draft, 1966; 2 Folders (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
    - Lists of photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Photographs, undated; 2 Folders (Box 2, Folder 19, Box 191, Folder 18)
    - Discarded drawings, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Index, chronology, preface, additional readings and sources, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - "Salinas corrections", 2006 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - "Ray's comments", 2001; 2 Folders (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Second edition revisions, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Cover proofs, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Reviews, 1966-1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Revised draft, 2001?; 4 Folders (Box 3, Folder 6-9)
    - Foul matter, 2008; 6 Folders (Box 3, Folder 10-15)
    - First pass (author's set) - proofs, 15 November 2007; 3 Folders (Box 3, Folder 16-18)
    - First pass - annotated proofs, 15 November 2007; 2 Folders (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
    - First pass - annotated proofs, 15 November 2007 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Second pass (author's set) - proofs, 14 December 2007; 3 Folders (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
    - Penultimate draft - annotated typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
    - Second pass - annotated proofs, 14 December 2007; 3 Folders (Box 4, Folder 8-10)
    - Publishing correspondence, 2007-2008 (Box 191, Folder 15)
    - Publicity and quotes, 2007-2008 (Box 191, Folder 16)
    - Line drawings and illustrations, undated (Box 191, Folder 17)
  - Two Thousand Years in Rome
    - Reviews, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Rough draft - annotated typescript, undated; 4 Folders (Box 4, Folder 13-16)
    - Revisions, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Revised draft - annotated typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 5, Folder 2-4)
    - Drawings, 1967? (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Galleys, 1968; 6 Folders (Box 191, Folders 2-7)
    - Research and notes, undated (Box 191, Folder 24)
  - Oriental Institute photographs, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - List of photographs for Temples, Tombs, and Hieroglyphs and Red Land, Black Land, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Reviews and publicity for Temples, Tombs, and Hieroglyphs and Red Land, Black Land, 1966-1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "Egyptian books - drawings", undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Temples, Tombs, and Hieroglyphs and Red Land, Black Land publishing correspondence, 2006 (Box 191, Folder 19)
  - Temples, Tombs, and Hieroglyphs and Red Land, Black Land acquisition and permissions, 2006-2007 (Box 191, Folder 20)
  - Temples, Tombs, and Hieroglyphs and Red Land, Black Land invoices, 2006-2007 (Box 191, Folder 21)
- Elizabeth Peters
  - The Jackal's Head
    - Annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
    - Master proofs, 3 April 1968; 2 Folders (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
    - Toronto Star Weekly serialisation, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Reviews and publicity, 1968-2001 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Cover proofs and sketches, 2001? (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Plot outlines, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Revised typescript, 1967; 2 Folders (Box 190, Folders 12-13)
    - Early draft, undated; 2 Folders (Box 190, Folders 14-15)
  - The Camelot Caper
    - Galleys, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Annotated typescript, 1968; 2 Folders (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Cover proofs and sketch, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Reviews, publicity, and publishing correspondence, 1969-2002 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Notes and research material, 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Plot outlines, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Dead Sea Cipher
    - Galley proofs, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
    - Cuts and revised draft - typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
    - Revised draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
    - Reviews, publicity, and publishing correspondence, 1970-2001 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Cover proofs and sketch, 2000? (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Notes and plot outlines, 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - The Night of Four Hundred Rabbits
    - Galley proofs, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Cover proof and publicity, 1971-2002 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Plot outlines and notes, 1970? (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 6, Folder 20-21)
    - Draft - annotated typescript (folder 1), undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Draft - annotated typescript (folder 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Draft - typescript, September 1970; 2 Folders (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
    - Star Weekly - Night of the Four Hundred Rabbits serialization, 1971 (Box 188)
  - Legend in Green Velvet
    - Cover proofs and sketches, 1999-2002 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Reviews and publicity, 1976? (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Rough draft and notes, undated; 2 Folders (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
    - Revised draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
  - Devil May Care
    - Rough draft and notes - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
    - Revised draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
    - Cover proofs and sketch, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Reviews, publicity, and publishing correspondence, 1983-2000 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Plot outlines, 1973-1976 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Summer of the Dragon
    - Rough draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 7, Folder 17-18)
    - Revised draft - typescript, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Plot outline and notes, January 1978 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Cover proofs and sketch, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Reviews and publicity, 1979-2000 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - The Love Talker
    - Cover proofs and sketch, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Reviews and publicity, 1981-2000 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Plot outline, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Draft - annotated typescript (folder 1), undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Draft - annotated typescript (folder 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Carbon copy - typescript, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - The Copenhagen Connection
    - Cover proofs, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Reviews and publicity, 1982-2001 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Draft, May 1981; 2 Folders (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
    - Revised draft - typescript, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Plot outlines and notes, 1981 (Box 192, Folder 2)
  - Jacqueline Kirby Series
    - The Seventh Sinner
      - Galley proofs, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
      - Draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
      - Revised draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 8, Folder 13-14)
      - Plot outlines and notes, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Cover proofs and sketch, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Reviews and publicity, 1972-2005 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - The Murders of Richard III
      - Cover proofs, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Reviews and publicity, 1973-2004 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Notes and research material, 1966-1974?; 2 Folders (Box 8, Folder 20-21)
      - Second revision - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 8, Folder 22-23)
      - Draft - annotated typescript (folder 1), undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - Draft - annotated typescript (folders 2-3), undated; 2 Folders (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
      - Plot outlines and notes, 1973? (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Die for Love
      - Draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
      - Revised draft - typescript, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Cover proofs, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Reviews and publicity, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Notes, undated (Box 192, Folder 1)
    - Naked Once More
      - First draft - annotated typescript, June 1988; 3 Folders (Box 9, Folder 9-11)
      - Second draft - annotated typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 9, Folder 12-14)
      - Foul matter, undated; 4 Folders (Box 9, Folder 15-18)
      - Reviews and publicity, 1989-2005; 2 Folders (Box 9, Folder 19-20)
      - Cover proofs, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - Titles for "the sequel to Naked", undated (Box 190, Folder 8)
  - Vicky Bliss Series
    - Borrower of the Night
      - Early draft - annotated typescript, 1960s (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - "Death of a Ghost" - carbon copy, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Second draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
      - Revised draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
      - Foul matter, undated; 2 Folders (Box 10, Folder 7-8)
      - Plot outline and notes, 1971-1973 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Cover proofs, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Reviews and publicity, 1973-2002 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Street of the Five Moons
      - Rough draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
      - Revised draft - annotated typescript (copy), undated; 2 Folders (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
      - Revised draft - typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 10, Folder 16-17)
      - Reviews and publicity, 1978-1998 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Plot outline, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - Cover proofs, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - Treatment by Leigh Chapman, 1992 (Box 190, Folder 11)
    - Silhouette in Scarlet
      - Reviews, publicity, and publishing correspondence, 1983-2000 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - Cover proofs and sketches, 2000? (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - Plot outlines and notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - Rough draft - annotated typescript, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - Revised draft - typescript, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Trojan Gold
      - Cover proofs, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Reviews and publicity, 1987-2005 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Rough draft - annotated typescript, undated; 4 Folders (Box 11, Folder 3-6)
      - Revised draft - annotated typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 11, Folder 7-9)
    - Night Train to Memphis
      - First draft - annotated typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 11, Folder 10-12)
      - Second draft - annotated typescript, undated; 4 Folders (Box 11, Folder 13-16)
      - First revision - annotated typescript (folders 1-2), undated; 2 Folders (Box 11, Folder 17-18)
      - First revision - annotated typescript (folder 3), undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Second revision - typescript, undated; 4 Folders (Box 12, Folder 2-5)
      - Second revision (second copy) - typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 12, Folder 6-8)
      - Plot outlines and notes, 1993? (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Cover proofs and correspondence with cover artist, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Publicity tour, 1994; 3 Folders (Box 12, Folder 11-13)
      - Publicity tour - receipts, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Publicity tour - business cards, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Research materials, 1991-1993 (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - "Songs", undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - "Maps and schedules", 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Reviews, publicity, and publishing correspondence, 1992-2004; 2 Folders (Box 12, Folder 19-20)
    - Laughter of Dead Kings
      - First revision - annotated typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 13, Folder 1-3)
      - Second revision - typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Third pass - annotated typescript, 24 April 2008; 2 Folders (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
      - First pass, 5 March 2008; 2 Folders (Box 13, Folder 7-8)
      - Revised draft - annotated typescript, February 2008; 3 Folders (Box 13, Folder 9-11)
        Scope and Contents
        Includes CD
      - Foul matter, 2008; 3 Folders (Box 13, Folder 12-14)
      - Notes and style sheet, 2007? (Box 13, Folder 15)
      - Reviews, publicity, and publishing correspondence, 2008-2009; 2 Folders (Box 13, Folder 16-17)
      - Cover proofs and sketch, undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
      - "Sales", 2008 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - "Next Vicky" - notes and research, 1995-2007 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Amelia Peabody Series
    - Crocodile on the Sandbank
      - Cover proofs, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Reviews and publicity, 1991-2004 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Introduction, 1990? (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Layout sketches, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Revised draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 14, Folder 6-7)
      - Revised draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
      - Plot outlines and notes, 1973? (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - Rough draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 14, Folder 11-12)
      - Woman's Own - Crocodile on the Sandbank serialization, 1976 (Box 188)
      - Marked-up copy, undated (Box 190, Folder 10)
    - The Curse of the Pharaohs
      - Cover proofs, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - Reviews and publicity, 1981-1985 (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - Introduction, undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - Plot outlines and notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - Rough draft - annotated typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 14, Folder 17-19)
      - Revised draft - typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 14, Folder 20-21)
    - The Mummy Case
      - Cover proofs, undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
      - Reviews and publicity, 1984-1998? (Box 14, Folder 23)
      - First pass - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 14, Folder 24-25)
      - Second pass - page proofs (folder 1), 2007 (Box 14, Folder 26)
      - Second pass - page proofs (folder 2), undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Plot outlines and notes, 1983? (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Rough draft - annotated typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 15, Folder 3-5)
      - Revised draft - typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 15, Folder 6-7)
      - Foul matter, 2007-2008; 2 Folders (Box 15, Folder 8-9)
    - Lion in the Valley
      - Reviews and publicity, 1985-2008 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Cover proofs, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Rough draft - annotated typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 15, Folder 12-14)
      - Revised draft - typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 15, Folder 15-16)
    - The Deeds of the Disturber
      - Cover proofs, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - Reviews, publicity, and publishing correspondence, 1986-2000? (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - Plot outlines, notes, and style sheets, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
      - First draft - annotated typescript (folders 1-3), undated; 3 Folders (Box 15, Folder 20-22)
      - First draft - annotated typescript (folder 4), 1960-2011 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Revised draft - typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 16, Folder 2-4)
      - Foul matter, 1989; 4 Folders (Box 16, Folder 5-8)
    - The Last Camel Died at Noon
      - First draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 16, Folder 9-10)
      - Final revision - typescript, undated; 4 Folders (Box 16, Folder 11-14)
      - Page proofs, 1991; 2 Folders (Box 16, Folder 15-16)
      - Second draft - annotated typescript (folder 1), undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
      - Second draft - annotated typescript (folders 2-3), undated; 2 Folders (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
      - Cover proofs, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Introduction, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - "'The Last Camel Died at Noon' as Lost World Adventure Pastiche" by Gary Hoppenstand, 14 December 2000 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Plot outlines, notes, style sheets, and research materials, 1990-2002 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Reviews and publicity, 1991-1994; 2 Folders (Box 17, Folder 7-8)
    - The Snake, the Crocodile and the Dog
      - Galleys - author's set, 24 August 1993; 3 Folders (Box 17, Folder 9-11)
      - First draft - annotated typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 17, Folder 12-14)
      - Second draft - annotated typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 17, Folder 15-17)
      - Revised draft - typescript (folders 1-3), undated; 3 Folders (Box 17, Folder 18-20)
      - Revised draft - typescript (folder 4), undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - German translation - typescript, 1992? (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Cover proofs, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Reviews, publicity, and publishing correspondence, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Plot outlines, notes, and research materials, 1991? (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - The Hippopotamus Pool
      - Galley proofs, undated; 3 Folders (Box 18, Folder 6-8)
      - Third draft - typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 18, Folder 9-11)
      - First draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 18, Folder 12-13)
      - Revised draft - typescript, undated; 4 Folders (Box 18, Folder 14-17)